Guide to the Ray DiPalma Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 2005 Acquisition, 1960-2005; 37.97; (45 boxes) + 7 broadside folders
  - Artists' Books
    - Unsewn books, 2000, undated (Box 25)
    - "Detail", 1991, 2000; 2 (Box 25)
    - "Foundry", 1993 (Box 25)
    - "Detail", 1991 (Box 25)
    - "Zo", 1992 (Box 25)
    - Untitled, 1992 (Box 25)
    - "15 Collages", 1991 (Box 25)
    - Manuscript and exercise books, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Untitled, 1976-1991; 13 (Box 25)
    - "Detail", 1991 (Box 25)
    - Untitled, 2001 (Box 25)
    - "The Blue Arrow", 1979 (Box 25)
    - Untitled red books, undated; 10 (Box 25)
    - Untitled, undated; 4 (Box 25)
    - "Printed Matter", undated (Box 25)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 25)
    - "10 Faces", untitled (Box 25)
    - Untitled, 1976-1991, undated; 8 (Box 25)
    - The Fairbanks Bicycle, undated; 2 (Box 25)
    - Untitled, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - The Fairbanks Bicycle, undated (Box 26)
    - "Ten Pyramids", 1977 (Box 26)
    - Artists' books and related material, 1979-1993, undated (Box 26)
    - Untitled, undated; 9 (Box 26)
    - "Trois Billets Deux Champs", undated (Box 26)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 26)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 26)
    - "The Life & Times of an Involuntary Genius", undated (Box 26)
    - Untitled, undated; 3 (Box 26)
    - "Atlas", 1995 (Box 26)
    - " Letters: Hard Copy for Printers", 1998 (Box 26)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 26)
    - "La Zyrq", undated (Box 26)
    - Untitled, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - "Zeffhir", 1991 (Box 26)
    - Untitled, undated; 15 (Box 26)
    - Untitled, undated; 3 (Box 27)
    - Van Rijn Fijne Mosterd, undated (Box 27)
    - Untitled, undated; 3 (Box 27)
    - Drop Cloth, undated (Box 27)
    - Faros Papel Arroz, undated (Box 27)
    - Untitled, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - Flirt, undated (Box 27)
    - Sunshine, undated (Box 27)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 27)
    - Miles from Columbus to, undated (Box 27)
    - Untitled, undated; 6 (Box 27)
  - Graphic Works
    - General
      - "Artists' Books USA", 1978-1980 (Box 28)
      - "Art Words and Bookworks," initial version, undated (Box 28)
      - "Plenary Indulgence", 1975 (Box 28)
      - Graphics from Maya Anderson and Alexandre Delay, 1993-1999, undated (Box 28)
      - "Notes at the Hotel Oxford", 1969 Augest (Box 28)
      - "Sketchbook With Works Done in Rubber Stamp", 1989 August (Box 28)
      - "The Ray Society", undated (Box 28)
      - "Detail", 1991 (Box 28)
      - "Towards a Personal Alphabet", 1989 (Box 28)
      - Crayon drawings, undated (Box 28)
      - Other graphic works, undated; 10 (Box 28)
      - Graphic postcards, undated; 6 (Box 28)
      - Small graphic books, 1976; 3 (Box 28)
    - Various Stages
      - Poems (1988-1994) (Box 29)
      - Blank transparencies, undated (Box 29)
      - "The Birthday Notations", undated (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 29)
      - "Across the Lens", 1997-1999 (Box 29)
      - "Black Work", undated (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 29)
      - Hôtel des Ruines, undated (Box 29)
      - "Marquee a Score" and "The Sargasso Transcries", 1977, 1984 (Box 29)
      - Untitled, undated; 2 (Box 29)
      - Various poems, 1993, undated (Box 29)
      - Indiscretions of the Minotaur, 1990, undated; 2 (Box 29)
      - "The Birthday Notations", undated (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 29)
      - Unused envelopes, undated (Box 29)
      - "Startle Luna", 1984 (Box 29)
      - Joe Brainard's Art, undated (Box 29)
      - Poetry calendar, 2000 June (Box 29)
      - "Two Works", undated (Box 29)
      - "Havana...Sur Hoy-Hoy...1953", undated (Box 29)
      - "The Black Swan Ray", 2004 (Box 29)
      - Janvier Zéro, undated (Box 29)
      - "Look Brand", undated (Box 29)
      - "Gravure sur bois d'une scène dans un cirque à la fin du XX siécle"..., 1993 (Box 29)
      - DiPalma photographs, undated (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 3 (Box 29)
      - "Nine Days" and "Ten Collages", 2002, undated (Box 29)
      - "Hotel Film", undated (Box 29)
      - "Codex" and "Uccelli", 1989 (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 (Box 29)
      - "Gravure sur bois d'une scène dans un cirque à la fin du XX siécle"..., undated (Box 29)
      - "Uccelli", 1989 (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous, 1993-1996, undated; 3 (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous emails, 1998 (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 (Box 30)
      - DiPalma photographs, undated (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 (Box 30)
      - "Gravure sur bois d'une scène dans un cirque à la fin du XX siécle"..., undated (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 30)
      - "Nervals Kith Aldo" and other works, undated (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 6 (Box 30)
    - Finished Works
      - "Japanese Notebook - Tower of Trolleys", 1978 (Box 30)
      - "Barks and Lapels", undated (Box 30)
      - "Seven Graphic Works", 1991 (Box 30)
      - Calendars, undated (Box 30)
      - "Zop", 1985 (Box 30)
      - Plastic Bag 1, undated; 3 (Box 30)
      - "Tzuuka", 1978-2000 (Box 30)
      - "July 10, 1990", 1990 July 10 (Box 30)
      - "July 9, 1990", 1990 July 9 (Box 30)
      - "July 8, 1990", 1990 July 8 (Box 30)
      - "July 7, 1990", 1990 July 7 (Box 30)
      - "July 6, 1990", 1990 July 6 (Box 30)
      - "July 5, 1990", 1990 July 5 (Box 30)
      - "July 4, 1990", 1990 July 4 (Box 30)
      - "July 3, 1990", 1990 July 3 (Box 30)
      - "July 2, 1990", 1990 July 2 (Box 30)
      - "July 1, 1990", 1990 July 1 (Box 30)
      - "June 30, 1990", 1990 June 30 (Box 30)
      - "June 29, 1990", 1990 June 29 (Box 30)
      - "June 28, 1990", 1990 June 28 (Box 30)
      - "June 27, 1990", 1990 June 27 (Box 30)
      - "June 26, 1990", 1990 June 26 (Box 30)
      - "June 25, 1990", 1990 June 25 (Box 30)
      - "June 24, 1990", 1990 June 24 (Box 30)
      - "June 23, 1990", 1990 June 23 (Box 30)
      - "June 22, 1990", 1990 June 22 (Box 30)
      - "June 21, 1990", 1990 June 21 (Box 30)
      - "June 20, 1990", 1990 June 20 (Box 30)
      - "June 19, 1990", 1990 June 19 (Box 30)
      - "June 18, 1990", 1990 June 18 (Box 30)
      - "June 17, 1990", 1990 June 17 (Box 30)
      - "June 16, 1990", 1990 June 16 (Box 30)
      - "June 15, 1990", 1990 June 15 (Box 30)
      - "June 14, 1990", 1990 June 14 (Box 30)
      - "June 13, 1990", 1990 June 13 (Box 30)
      - "June 12, 1990", 1990 June 12 (Box 30)
      - "June 11, 1990", 1990 June 11 (Box 30)
      - "June 10, 1990", 1990 June 10 (Box 31)
      - "June 9, 1990", 1990 June 9 (Box 31)
      - "June 8, 1990", 1990 June 8 (Box 31)
      - "June 7, 1990", 1990 June 7 (Box 31)
      - "June 6, 1990", 1990 June 6 (Box 31)
      - "June 5, 1990", 1990 June 5 (Box 31)
      - "June 4, 1990", 1990 June 4 (Box 31)
      - "June 3, 1990", 1990 June 3 (Box 31)
      - "June 2, 1990", 1990 June 2 (Box 31)
      - "June 1, 1990", 1990 June 1 (Box 31)
      - "May 31, 1990", 1990 May 31 (Box 31)
      - "May 30, 1990", 1990 May 30 (Box 31)
      - "Horizon Sound Texts", undated (Box 31)
      - Group, undated (Box 31)
      - Collages, 1990-1991; 2 (Box 31)
      - Xerox art, undated (Box 31)
      - "A Packet", 1968 (Box 31)
      - "Circus Circus", 2001 (Box 31)
      - "Collage and Collages", 1991 (Box 31)
      - "Three Songs", 1991 (Box 31)
      - "Startle Luna", 1984 (Box 31)
      - "Matak", 1976 (Box 31)
      - Baseball, undated (Box 31)
      - "Foreign Works", undated (Box 31)
      - "Palm Works", undated (Box 31)
      - Miscellaneous, 1977-1991, undated; 11 (Box 31)
      - Books of drawings, 1976; 6 (Box 31)
    - Initial Versions
      - "Jack's Corners", 1993 (Box 32)
      - "308", 1996 (Box 32)
      - "Ray DiPalma's Komicks", undated (Box 32)
      - "Map Text", 1996 (Box 32)
      - "RSVP", 1982 (Box 32)
      - Periodical clippings, 1966-1969 (Box 32)
      - Xerox art, undated (Box 32)
      - Poems, 2001-2003, undated (Box 32)
      - Circus, undated (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous poems, 1992-1997, undated (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous, 1990-2002, undated; 20 (Box 32)
      - "Exhibition catalogue", undated (Box 33)
      - Cigar box with three printing blocks, undated (Box 33)
      - "Marquee" wood block, undated (Box 33)
      - Unlabelled box, undated (Box 33)
      - Unlabelled box with "Finished Graphic Works", undated (Box 33)
  - Personal Papers
    - Notebooks and journals, 1966-19791967; 16 (Box 34)
    - Notebooks and journals, 19781-2004; 20 (Box 35)
    - "2005," loose notes, 3 (Box 35)
    - Calendars and diaries, 1976-1988; 10 (Box 35)
    - Calendars and diaries, 1989-2000; 20 (Box 36)
  - Printed Material
    - Poetry reading and party announcement, 1968 (Box 37)
    - Announcement of DiPalma et al. 1990 NYFA grant recipients
    - "Art Metropole", 1985 (Box 37)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club News, 1980-1981 (Box 37)
    - Centre International de poésie Marseille, 2000 (Box 37)
    - Poesia & Cinema Americains, 1998 October (Box 37)
    - Clippings, 1996, undated; 2 (Box 37)
    - Doones Archive, undated (Box 37)
    - "Endgame," DiPalma's acting copy, 1967 (Box 37)
    - Flyers: Nouveaux Poetes Americains, undated (Box 37)
    - Comix and collages, undated (Box 37)
    - "Mail, Etc. & Art", 1979-1980 (Box 37)
    - Loose correspondence, 1986-1999 (Box 37)
    - Maya Anderson Exhibition Catalogue, 1997 (Box 37)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1982 (Box 37)
    - Notes, Mai 1986, 1986 May (Box 37)
    - "Poetry Calendar", 1999 June (Box 37)
    - Posters, 1979-1996 (Box 37)
    - Press release, 1988 January 25 (Box 37)
    - Sun and Moon Press, 1991 (Box 37)
    - TIME magazine, 1981 September 21 (Box 37)
    - Beneveniste, undated (Box 37)
    - "Centre International de Poesie Marseille", 1998 October (Box 37)
    - "Translation" Scott, John A, undated (Box 37)
    - "Janviero", undated (Box 37)
    - "Anacapa Books Catalogue #97", undated (Box 37)
    - Letter of reference written by Bruce Andrews, 1976 November (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous Material
    - "Carnival", 1973 (Box 38)
    - Sinister characters, undated (Box 38)
    - "A Heartfelt Hangover Sweet", 1976 November 25 (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987-1990, undated (Box 38)
    - Flyers, brochures, etc., 1980-1995 (Box 38)
    - Printed material, 1978-1998, undated; 1; (1 compact disc) (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous poems and artwork, 1971, undated (Box 38)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 38)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1997, undated (Box 38)
      Includes letters from Billy Collins, Noima Cole, Johanna Drucker, Harry Reese, Alan Davies, Patty Oldenberg, Robert Creeley, Arthur Vogelsang, Thomas D. Clark, and others
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1977-2003 (Box 38)
    - DiPalma's CV, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - Bibliographic records for DiPalma's works at Brown University Library, 1997 July 16 (Box 38)
    - "Le Sol Du Jardin", undated (Box 38)
    - Photos, undated (Box 38)
    - Photos of Vincent and Gabrielle Dussol, 2003 (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous art work, undated (Box 38)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 38)
    - Nicola Frangione, undated (Box 38)
    - "First Annual Conference of the College of Neglected Science", 1997 May (Box 38)
    - Empty folders, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - "1/1" by Nick Piombino, 1993 September 27 (Box 38)
    - Vangelisti's "Some Remarks on Ray DiPalma's ' Motion of the Cypher '", 1996 (Box 38)
    - "Workbook" by Brandfass, Elizabeth, undated (Box 38)
    - "Certainly Metaphysics", 1972 March 8 (Box 38)
    - "A*C*E" by Raworth, Tom, 1974 (Box 38)
    - "A Gathering of Young Poets" posters, undated
    - Announcement "Charting", undated (Box 38)
    - Announcements, flyers, etc., 1985-2003; 2 (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous art, 1972 (Box 38)
    - Printed ephemera, 1969-1998, undated; 2 (Box 38)
  - Audiovisual Material
    Box 39 (reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information
    - "Selections from reading by Ray DiPalma at BGSU, Part I", 1970 July 29; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002104617445)
      Box 39 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Selections from a reading by Ray DiPalma at BGSU, Part 2", 1970 July 29; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002104617452)
    - "Annotated working script and reel-to-reel audiotape made for stage: video production of Krapp's Last Tape, University of Iowa", 1968 Spring; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002104617460)
    - "D.C. Reading," audiocassette, 1977 October; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002104617411)
      Box 40 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Public Language," audiocassette, 1982 January 11; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002104617429)
    - "WBAI", 1981 November 23; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002104617437)
    - "Ed Vogelsang," record, undated (Box 41 (Record Album Storage))
  - Oversize, 0.5; (2 boxes) + 7 broadside folders
    - Un bureau sur l'Atlantique, undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Other art work, undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Original art work from Alexander Delay, undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Original collages for Labyrinth Radio, 1979-1980 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - "Rag Time" and "Certainly Metaphysics", undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - "Miscellaneous Art", undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Stats; drawings for Janvier Zéro, undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - "Edward II" poster, undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Washington Review, 1991 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Soho News, 1980 December (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Boston Review, Vol. 27, Nos. 3-4, 2002 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Washington Review, Fall 1976 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Washington Review, Winter 1975-76, 1975-1976 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - "Voice Choices", 1978 August 2 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Chax Press, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Vincent Dussol correspondence, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Hewitt; Winch; Bergland correspondence, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Michael Lally correspondence, 1978-1995 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Claude Royet-Journoud correspondence, 1970-1992 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Steve Schrader correspondence, 1972 October 16 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Ron Silliman correspondence, 1977, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Unsorted, 1969-2003, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Unsorted, 1978, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Unidentified manuscript drafts, 1988 August (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Raik, page proofs, 1989 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Newspapers, 1969-1970, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - "Palm Works", 1980 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Periodical clippings, 1966, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Announcement of DiPalma et al. 1990 NYFA grant recipients (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Newspaper clippings, 1982 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Flyers, brochures, etc., 2000 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - "A Gathering of Young Poets" posters, 1972 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Announcements, flyers, etc., 1972-2003, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Correspondence: Frangione, 1980 (Box 44(Broadside))
    - Mail Art correspondence, 1978, undated (Box 45 (Broadside))
    - Miscellaneous, 1977-2003, undated (Box 46 (Broadside))
    - Miscellaneous, 1972-1995, undated (Box 47 (Broadside))
    - Miscellaneous material, 1990-2003, undated (Box 48 (Broadside))
    - Posters, 1992-1994, undated (Box 49 (Broadside))
    - Nicola Frangione, 1981 (Box 50 (Broadside))
  - Restricted Fragile Material, 0.42; (2 boxes)
    - Computer Media, undated
      - The Blue Slope (1-10) Word 5.0, 2005-ycal-0621-b-0001; 1 (Box 51)
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - The Little Magazine Volume 21 The egg of thought becoming human, 2005-ycal-0621-b-0002; 1 (Box 51)
    - Untitled mixed-media object, undated (Box 52)
- July 2006 Acquisition, 1998-2002; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically.
  The July 2006 Acquisition contains a small amount of printed material.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 925.
  Purchased from Ray DiPalma on the George B. Alvord Fund, 2006.
  - "The Impossible City", 1998 (Box 53)
  - Postcard, undated (Box 53)
  - Quaderno, 1999 (Box 53)
  - "Vault of the Disolvable Novel", 2002 (Box 53)